<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Freedom Fighters of India</string>
    <string name="bal">
        Name :				Bal Gangadhar Tilak,

        Born :			23-July-1856,
        Place of Birth :	    Ratnagiri and Maharashtra,
        Nationality :		    Indian
        Died :				1-Aug-1920
    </string>

    <string name="bal_e">
        Education : Deccan College, Pune and LL.B degree from Government Law College of University of Mumbai.
                    Despite two attempts he did not succeed in qualifying in his M. A.
    </string>
    <string name="bal_b">
        Biography :
	        Bal Gangadhar Tilak also known as Lokmanya Tilak was born in Ratnagiri, Maharashtra on July 23, 1856. He is known for his famous quote " Self Rule is our birthright, and We shall have it! " He was reverently addressed as Lokmanya (or "Beloved of the people" or "Revered by the world").
	        After completing his graduation, Tilak began teaching in a private school in Pune and went on to become a journalist. He was very vocal in his criticism of the Western education system and set up the Deccan Education Society to educate India youth. Tilak founded the Marathi daily Kesari (Lion), in the pages of which he actively propagated the cause of freedom. He joined the Indian National Congress. He was known for his hardcore Hindu views. In 1907, the Congress Party split into the two factions.
	        The British authorities charged Tilak with sedition and he was imprisoned from 1908 to 1914 in Mandalay, Burma. He re-joined the Indian National Congress in 1916 and helped to found the All India Home Rule League in 1916-18 . Tilak was not in favour of Mahatma Gandhi strategy of non-violent protest. He wrote many books on Indian culture, history and Hinduism like The Orion or Researches into the antiquities of the Vedas (1893), Arctic Home in the Vedas, Geetarahasya and others. He passed away on August 1, 1920.
    </string>
    <string name="Name1">
        Bal Gangadhar Tilak
    </string>
    <string name="bipin_name">Bipin Chandra Pal</string>
    <string name="bipin_data">
        Name :				Bipin Chandra Pal,
        Born : 				7-Nov-1858,
        Place of Birth : 		Sylhet,
        Died : 				20-May-1932.
    </string>
    <string name="bipin1">
        Education : Received school education in Sylhet. He went to the Presidency College for graduation but left it midway.
                    He worked as the headmaster of a high school for several years at different schools. He has also worked as a librarian and secretary for the Calcutta Public Library
                    Between 1890 and 1891, he worked as a librarian and secretary for the Calcutta Public Library.
                    Jail Journey	He was jailed for a period of six months for not putting forward the evidence thet he possessed against Sri Aurobindo in the Vande Mataram sedition case.
    </string>
    <string name="bipin2">
        Biography :
				Bipin Chandra Pal (1858-1932) was a noted politician, journalist, an eminent orator and one of the three famous patriots, known as the trilogy of Lal Bal Pal. The other two were Lala Lajpat Rai and Bal Gangadhar Tilak. He was one of the main architects of the Swadeshi movement. He stood against the partition of West Bengal.
				Pal was born on November 7, 1858 in at Sylhet (now in Bangladesh). He came to Calcutta and got admitted in the Presidency college but left studies before graduating. However he had remarkable Literacy competence and studied various books extensively. He started his career as school master andworked as a librarian in the Calcutta Public Library. Here he came in contact with Keshav Chandra Senand others like Shivnath Shastri, B.K.Goswami and S.N.Banerjee. Their influence attracted him to join active politics. Soon he got inspired by the extremist patriotism of Tilak, Lala and Aurobindo. In 1898 he went to England to study comparative theology but came back to preach ideal of Swadeshi through himself in the non cooperation movement due to his difference of view points with other leaders of the movement.
				A journalist himself, Pal used his profession in spreading patriotic feelings and social awareness. He was the editor of the Democrat, the Independent and many other journals and newspapers. He published a biography of Queen Victoria in Bangla. Swaraj and the Present Situation and The Soul of India are the two of his many books written by him.
				Pal had a never say die attitude and he lived by his Principle. He revolted against the evils and ill practices of Hinduism. He was a member of the Brahmo Samaj and believed in the equality of men and women. He encouraged widow marriages and female education. India lost one of its most ardent patriot when he passed away in 1932.

    </string>
    <string name="azad_name">Chandra Shekhar Azad</string>
    <string name="azad">
        Name : 			Chandra Shekhar Azad ,
        Born : 			23rd July 1906 ,
        Nationality : 			Indian ,
        Died : 				27 February 1931 (aged 24)
    </string>
    <string name="azad1">
        Biography : A daring freedom fighter and a fearless revolutionary, Chandra Shekhar was born on 23 July 1906 in Bhavra, Madhya Pradesh. Involved in incidents such as Kakori Train Robbery, assembly bomb incident and the shooting of Saunders at Lahore, to avenge the killing of Lala Lajpat Rai, he was the face of revolutionary India.
					Son of Pandit Sitaram Tiwari and Jagarani Devi, he received his early education at Bhavra and was sent to the Sanskrit Pathshala at Varanasi, Uttar Pradesh for higher studies. At a very young age he got involved in revolutionary activities. He joined the non-cooperation movement launched by Mahatma Gandhi. Caught by the British police while indulging in revolutionary activities he was sentenced to 15 whiplashes as his first punishment. At that time he was merely 15-years-old. It was after this incident that Chandra Shekhar assumed the title of Azad and came to be known as Chandra Shekhar Azad.
					Disillusioned with Mahatma Gandhis suspension of non-cooperation movement due to Chauri-Chaura incident, he turned into an extremist. Chandra Shekhar Azad was a believer in socialism; he along with other revolutionaries formed The Hindustan Socialist Republican Association. He was a mentor to many revolutionaries including Bhagat Singh. He wanted complete independence for India by any means. Chandra Shekhar Azad killed British Assistant Superintendent of Police John Poyantz Saunders to avenge the death of Lala Lajpat Rai. He remained a terror for the British Government as long as he was alive. On 27 February 1931, betrayed by one of the associates, he was besieged by the British police in Alfred Park, Allahabad. He fought valiantly but seeing no other way he shot himself and fulfilled his resolve to die a free man.
					He is still a hero for millions of Indians and many movies such as Shaheed Bhagat Singh, The Legend of Bhagat Singh and 23rd March 1931 has characters based on his life.

    </string>
    <string name="nehru_name">Jawaharlal Nehru</string>
    <string name="nehru">
        Name : 				Jawaharlal Nehru ,
        Born : 				14 November 1889 ,
        Place of Birth : 		Allahabad ,
        Nationality : 			Indian ,
        Died : 				27 May 1964.
    </string>
    <string name="nehru1">
        Biography : 			Jawaharlal Nehru, one of the central figures of Indian politics during India struggle for independence and the first Prime Minister of India was born on 14th November 1889 in Allahabad. As a son of an influential Indian barrister and politician he grew up in the lap of luxury with governesses and tutors. His early schooling was in India and at the age of 15 he went to England to attend the Harrow School. Later he joined Trinity College to study natural science. After this he joined Inner Temple in London to train himself as a barrister. He returned to India in 1912 and joined Allahabad High Court Bar, Uttar Pradesh. On 8th February 1916, at the age of 27 he married Kamla Kaul. Next year their only daughter, Indira, was born. 1920 proved to be the turning point in the life of anglicized Jawaharlal Nehru. Once traveling in train he overheard General Dyre gloating over Jallianwala Bagh massacre. He vowed to fight the imperial rule and joined Indian politics. He was strongly influenced by the Gandhian views and was the supporter of Mahatma Gandhi in freedom struggle. Under the influence of Gandhi he, along with his family, abandoned his western possessions and lifestyle and started using Swadeshi. He was a very good orator and a prominent organizer. Soon he became one of the popular political leaders of north India. In 1924 he was elected as the president of Municipal Corporation of Allahabad. Dissatisfied by British officials and corruption amongst civil servants, he resigned from his post within two years. He was not in the favor of dominion status for India within the British Empire, as recommended by his father. He strongly criticized the Nehru report prepared by his father Motilal Nehru
					Jawaharlal Nehru, the man who made a tryst with destiny, was a leader who kept his promise and led India to freedom. The first Prime Minister ofIndia, he came to the forefront of the Indian freedom struggle after Jallianwalah Bagh massacre. Devoted to the cause of freedom, he was a representative of a whole new generation of India. World Peace and all round development of India were the main concerns of this great statesman. Chacha Nehru, as he was fondly called by children, was amongst the prominent names behind the establishment of the Non Aligned Movement (NAM).
    </string>

    <string name="lala_name">Lala Lajpat Rai</string>
    <string name="lala">
        Name :   					Lala Lajpat Rai,
        Born :   					28/01/65,
        Nationality : 				Indian,
        Died : 					17/11/1928.
    </string>

    <string name="lala1">
        Biography :
						Lala Lajpat Rai, popularly known as Punjab Kesari, was a famous freedom fighter of India. He was one of the three extremist members of the Indian National Congress who gave their life for the independence of India along with other two members Bal Gangadhar Tilak and Bipin Chandra Pal. They were collectively known as Lal-Bal-Pal. These extremist members of the Indian National Congress wanted self-government for India and they were the first Indian leaders to demand the complete political independence for the country.
						He was one of the important members of the Hindu Maha Sabha. Lala Lajpat Rai was the president of the All India Trade Union Congress in 1920. He was the leader of Punjab in protests against the Jallianwala Bagh Massacre. He also led the non-cooperation movement in Punjab. Lala Lajpat Rai was highly influenced by socialist reformer Swami Dayananda Saraswati and was the strong supporter of the Arya Samaj movement in Punjab.
    </string>
    <string name="gandhi_name">Mohandas Karamchand Gandhi</string>
    <string name="gandhi">
        Name : 					    Mahatma Gandhi,
        Full Name : 				Mohandas Karamchand Gandhi,
        Born :  					2/Oct/1869,
        Nationality : 				Indian,
        Died : 					30/Jan/1948.
    </string>
    <string name="gandhi1">
        Education :
						In November 1887, the 18-year-old Gandhi graduated from high school in Ahmedabad. In January 1888, he enrolled at Samaldas College in Bhavnagar State, then the sole degree-granting institution of higher education in the region. But he dropped out and returned to his family in Porbandar.
						University College London. Samaldas College Bhavnagar, Gujarat.
    </string>

    <string name="gandhi2">
        Biography :
						History remembers Mahatma Gandhi as a great political and spiritual leader of India. Renowned for his non-violent campaigns of civil disobedience, people all across the world were impressed by his charisma, courage and the ability to influence peoples conscience. Albert Einsteins comment on Gandhi: "I believe that Gandhis views were the most enlightened of all the political men in our time. We should strive to do things in his spirit: not to use violence in fighting for our cause, but by non-participation in anything you believe is evil."
						The emergence of Gandhi played a pivotal role in the history of Indian Nationalism. The development of Indian Nationalism occurred in three separate phases. It was the third phase of Indian Nationalism that witnessed the rise of Mohandas Karamchand Gandhi, as the man who took the country by storm with his novel political ideologies centered on the cardinal principles of ahimsa and satyagraha.
    </string>
    <string name="gandhi3">
        Early Days :
						Mohan Das Karam Chand Gandhi, better known as Mahatma Gandhi was born on 2 October 1869 in Porbandar in Gujarat into the middle class Vaishya family. He was the son of Karamchand and Putlibai. He studied at the elementary school in Porbandar till the age of seven and later at Rajkot. He was married to Kasturba at the age of thirteen while still in high school. He matriculated from Samladas College in Bhavnager, Gujarat and went to England in 1888 to study law. Though his mother opposed this trip, but the opposition was overcome by Gandhis strict vow of not touching women, wine and meat in the foreign land. He passed his examination in 1891 and on 12 June 1891 sailed back to India.
    </string>

    <string name="pandey_name">Mangal Pandey</string>
    <string name="pandey">
        Name : 					Mangal Pandey,
        Born : 					19/July/1827,
        Nationality : 			Indian,
        Died : 					8/April/1857.
    </string>
    <string name="pandey1">
        Biography :
                        Mangal Pandey was born on 19 July 1827 in the village of Nagwa in the Ballia district of Uttar Pradesh. A sepoy in the 34th Regiment of the Bengal Native Infantry (BNI) of the English East India Company, he entered the annals of Indian history for attacking his British officers, sparking off the First War of Indian Independence or as the British termed it, the Sepoy Mutiny of 1857. At Barrackpore near Kolkata on 29 March 1857, Pandey attacked and injured his British sergeant, besides wounding an adjutant. A native soldier prevented him from killing the adjutant and the sergeant-major. He was arrested and sentenced to death. He was hanged on 8 April 1857.
    </string>

    <string name="motilal_name">Motilal Nehru</string>
    <string name="motilal">
        Name : 					Motilal Nehru,
        Born : 					24/September/1861,
        Nationality : 			Indian,
        Died : 					6/February/1931.
    </string>

    <string name="motilal1">
        Biography :
                        Motilal Nehru was an Indian independence activist and leader of the Indian National Congress. He was born on May 6,1861 in Agra, India.
			            He was one of the first Indians to receive Western education in India. He attended Muir College at Agra but failed to appear for his Bachelor of Arts degree examinations. Motilal Nehru then enlisted himself as a lawyer in the English courts. He became a barrister and settled in Allahabad. As a successful barrister, he earned the honor of appearing in the Privy Council of Great Britain.
			            Motilal Nehru was an active Indian independence activist. He was arrested by the British police during the Non-Cooperation Movement. Although Motilal Nehru was at first close to Mahatma Gandhi, later on he developed some differences with him and joined the Swaraj Party which tried to enter the British backed councils. The Swaraj Party became a failure; and Nehru returned to the Congress.
			            Motilal Nehru was the prime mover of the Nehru Commission (1928), the first constitution written by Indians which sought a dominion status for India within the British Empire. It was rejected by hard line Indians who saw it as an unfair document not representing the varied interests of the native Indian population.
			            Motilal Nehrus failing health kept him out of the pre-independent Indian politics when Mahatma Gandhi started the Salt Satyagraha. He was arrested in 1930, but was released quickly due to his deteriorating physical condition. This freedom fighter and a prominent figure in Indian National Congress passed away on February 6, 1931.
    </string>
    <string name="rani_name">Rani Lakshmi Bai</string>
    <string name="rani">
        Name : 					Rani Lakshmi Bai,
        Born : 					19/November/1828,
        Nationality : 			Indian,
        Died : 					18/June/1858.
    </string>

    <string name="rani1">
        Education : 				She was educated at home and was more independent in her childhood than others of her age; her studies included shooting, horsemanship, and fencing.
    </string>
    <string name="rani2">
        Biography :
			        Rani Lakshmi Bai was one of the leading warriors of the Indias first struggle for independence. A symbol of bravery, patriotism and honour, Rani Lakshmi Bai was born on 19 November 1828 at Poona. Her actual name was Manikarnika. Her father Moropant Tabme was a court advisor, and mother Bhagirathi was a scholarly woman. At a very early age she lost her mother. Her father raised her in an unconventional way and supported her to learn to ride elephants and horses and also to use weapons effectively. She grew up with Nana Sahib and Tatya Tope, who were active participants in the first revolt of independence.
                    In 1842, Rani Lakshmi Bai got married to Raja Gangadhar Rao who was the Maharaja of Jhansi. After her marriage, she came to be known as Lakshmi Bai. In 1851, she gave birth to a son but unfortunately he died in his fourth month. After this tragic incident, Damodar Rao was adopted by the Maharaja of Jhansi as his son. Moved by the death of his son and his poor health, Maharaja Gangadhar Rao also died on 21 November 1853. When the Maharaja died, Rani Lakshmi Bai was just eighteen years old, but she didnt lose her courage and took up her responsibility.
			        Lord Dalhousie, the Governor-General of India at that time, was a very shrewd person who tried to take advantage of the misfortune of Jhansi to expand the British Empire. The British rulers did not accept little Damodar Rao, as the legal heir of late Maharaja Gangadhar Rao and Rani Lakshmi Bai. Their plan was to annex Jhansi on the ground that it did not have any legal heir. In March 1854, Rani of Jhansi was granted an annual pension of 60,000 and was ordered to leave the Jhansi fort. She was firm on the decision not to give up the dominion of Jhansi to the British.
			        For strengthening the defence of Jhansi, Rani Lakshmi Bai assembled an army of rebellions, which also included women. For this great cause she was supported by brave warriors like Gulam Gaus Khan, Dost Khan, Khuda Baksh, Sunder-Mundar, Kashi Bai, Lala Bhau Bakshi, Moti Bai, Deewan Raghunath Singh and Deewan Jawahar Singh. She assembled 14,000 rebels and organised an army for the defence of the city.
			        In March 1858, when the British attacked Jhansi, Rani Lakshmi Bais army decided to fight and the war continued for about two weeks. The army fought very bravely, even though Jhansi lost to the British forces. After a fierce war when the British army entered Jhansi, Rani Lakshmi Bai, tied her son Damodar Rao to her back and fought bravely using two swords in both her hands. She escaped to the fortress of Kalpi under the cover of darkness and was accompanied by many other rebellions. She departed to Gwalior and a fierce battle was fought between the British and the Ranis army. On the unfortunate day of 17 June of 1858, this great warrior martyred her life for Indias freedom.
    </string>

    <string name="sardar_name">Sardar Vallabh Bhai Patel</string>
    <string name="sardar">
        Name : 					Sardar Vallabh Bhai Patel,
        Born :					31/October/1875,
        Nationality : 			Indian,
        Died : 					15/December/1950.
    </string>
    <string name="sardar1">
        Biography :
						Vallabhbhai Jhaverbhai Patel was one of the important social and political leaders of India. He played an important role in Indias struggle for freedom. He is believed to be born on 31 October 1875 at Nadiad, Gujarat and was often addressed as Sardar.
						He did his matriculation at the age of 22. He seemed to be an ordinary person to everyone around him, but had strong will power. He wanted to become a barrister. At the age of 36, he went to England to fulfill his dream and joined Middle Temple Inn. He completed his 36-month course in just 30 months. After returning to India he became one of the most successful barristers of Ahmedabad.
						Inspired by the work and philosophy of Mahatma Gandhi, he joined Indias struggle for independence. He organised peasants of Kheda, Bardoli and other parts of Gujarat and launched non-violent Civil Disobedience Movement in Gujarat, against the payment of raised tax, levied by the British government. He succeeded in his goal and the British Government suspended the payment of revenue for that year. With this he became one of the most influential leaders in Gujarat. In 1920 he became the president of Gujarat Pradesh Congress Committee and served in the post till 1945. He was a strong supporter of the Non -Cooperation Movement of Gandhi and worked against alcoholism, Untouchability and caste discrimination in Gujarat. He was elected as the municipal president of Ahmedabad in 1922, 1924 and 1927. When Mahatma Gandhi was in prison, he led the Satyagraha in Nagpur in 1923 against the British law, banning the raising of the Indian flag. He was elected as the President of India National Congress in 1931. He was at the forefront of the Congress all India election campaign in 1934 and 1937 and was a prominent leader in organising the Quit India Movement in 1942. He was arrested prior to the Quit India Movement and was released in 1945.
						After Indias independence, he became the first Home Minister and Deputy Prime Minister of India. He organised relief camps for refugees in Punjab and Delhi. He was the man behind the consolidation of 565 semi-autonomous princely states to form a united India. Patel was very attached to Mahatma Gandhi. After Mahatma Gandhis death his condition also started deteriorating, he suffered a major heart attack within two months of Gandhis death. He died on 15 December 1950. He was a man of courage and determination and in the true sense the Iron Man of India.
    </string>
    <string name="bhagat_name">Shaheed Bhagat Singh</string>
    <string name="bhagat">
        Name : 					Shaheed Bhagat Singh,
        Born : 					28/September/1907,
        Nationality : 			Indian,
        Died : 					23/March/1931.
    </string>

    <string name="bhagat1">
        Biography : 		His legacy prompted the Indian youth to fight for independence of India and today in the modern India; Bhagat Singh continues to be a youth icon. The Reserve Bank had issued Rs.5 denomination coins to commemorate Bhagat Singhs birth anniversary. The face of the coin displays the portrait of Bhagat Singh with words in Hindi and English.
                            Bhagat Singh is often termed as the youth icon or the revolutionary of the youth but his stature is one that equals some of the prominent names in the Indian freedom struggle. His patriotism was not restricted to the strong violent outburst against the British; he rather had a mind and intellect of a genius who could foresee division of India on communal lines which many of the much esteemed leaders of the time were unable to see. Keeping the cause of country ahead of the religion was another signs of his mature and rational mind. His educational qualifications establish the fact that his opinions and ideas were well thought and not just a product of hysterical mass movements.
    </string>
    <string name="bose_name">Nethaji Subhash Chandra Bose</string>
    <string name="bose">
        Name :					Subhash Chandra Bose,
        Born : 					23/January/1897,
        Nationality : 			Indian,
        Died : 					18/August/1945.
    </string>

    <string name="bose1">
        Education : 				Alma mater University of Calcutta and University of Cambridge. He continued his studies at this school which was run by the Baptist Mission up to 1909 and then shifted to the Ravenshaw Collegiate School. The day Subhas was admitted to this school, Beni Madhab Das, the headmaster, understood how brilliant and scintillating his genius was. After securing the second position in the matriculation examination in 1913, he got admitted to the Presidency College where he studied briefly.
    </string>

    <string name="bose2">
        Biography : 			Subhash Chandra Bose is one of the most dynamic leaders of Indias struggle of independence. He is popularly known as Netaji. He was born in Cuttack, in Orissa on January 23, 1897 to Janaki Nath Bose and Prabhavati Devi. His father was a famous lawyer and his mother was a religious lady. Among the fourteen siblings, he was the ninth child.
					        	Right from his childhood he was a bright student and was a topper in the matriculation examination from the whole of Calcutta province. He graduated from the Scottish Church College in Kolkata, West Bengal with a First Class degree in Philosophy. Influenced by the teachings of Swami Vivekananda, he was known for his patriotic zeal as a student. He went to England to accomplish his parents desire to appear in the Indian Civil Services. In 1920 he appeared for the competitive examination and stood fourth in the order of merit. Deeply moved by the Jallianwalla Bagh massacre in Punjab, Subhash Chandra Bose left his Civil Services apprenticeship midway and returned to India.
						        After he returned to India, Subhash Chandra Bose was influenced by Mahatma Gandhi views. He then joined the Indian National Congress and worked under the leadership of Deshbandhu Chittaranjan Das, who later became his political guru. He opposed the Dominion Status for India declared by the Congress under the guidance of the Motilal Nehru Committee. They were in favor of complete independence and nothing else. In 1930, during the Civil Disobedience he was sent to jail and released only after the Gandhi-Irwin pact was signed in 1931.
                                Subash Chandra Bose was exiled from India to Europe; he took advantage of this opportunity and tried to establish political and cultural ties between India and Europe by forming centers in the various capital cities of Europe. He was jailed for a year for not obeying the ban on his entry to India. Congress was elected in seven states during the general elections of 1937 and he was released. Defying the ban on his entry to India, Subash Chandra Bose returned to India and was again arrested and sent to jail for a year. After the General Elections of 1937, Congress came to power in seven states and he was released. Next year he was elected as the President of the Haripura Congress Session. He took a very stern decision and brought a resolution and asked Britishers to hand India over to the Indians within six months.
                                Following opposition to his rigid stand, he resigned from the post of president and formed the Forward Block. He fled to Germany via Afghanistan and tried to persuade Germany and Japan to cooperating against the British Empire. He then moved to Singapore from Germany in July 1943 and formed the Azad Hind Fauj (Indian National Army). The army comprised mainly of Indians who were prisoners of war. The army crossed the Burma border, and reached the Indian soil on March 18, 1944.
						        Japan and Germany were defeated in the Second World War and a result the INA could not fulfill its objective. On August 18, 1945, Subhash Chandra Bose was declared killed in an air crash over Taipei, Taiwan (Formosa). But there are people who believe that he is still alive and many Commissions were set up to find the truth but nothing could be found about his whereabouts.
    </string>

    <string name="success_message">Registration Successful</string>
    <string name="text_not_member">No account yet? Create one</string>
    <string name="text_already_member">Already a member? Login</string>
    <string name="error_email_exists">Email Already Exists</string>
    <string name="error_password_match">Password Does Not Matches</string>
    <string name="error_valid_email_password">Wrong Email or Password</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="text_hello">Hello,</string>
    <string name="text_title">Android Tutorials Hub</string>
    <string name="title_activity_indian_real_heros">Indian Real Heros</string>

</resources>
